# Bogdan Crudu

Email: bogdan@crudu.eu

Tel: +40 (728) 044 377

- 1. Work Experience
- 2. Volunteering
- 3. Education
- 4. Published Materials

### Overview

For hire: tech enthusiast with experience in software development and writing documentation. My passion is for building and shipping software. I like doing it on time and on budget by implementing solid design and architectural decisions backed by a trustable testing suite.

### **SKILS**

- Experience working with international teams
- Experience working with legacy systems and improving them over time
- Proficient in Ruby, Rails, Bash, HTML 5, CSS, Git, Md and Technical Documentation
- Experience working with Terraform, AWS Cloud infrastructure and Docker
- Comprehensive knowledge of object oriented design and software design patterns
- Proficiency maintaining and developing technical documentation
- Multilingual: Romanian, English, Italian, German, Spanish listed in order of proficiency

## Work Experience

### Modex | Bucharest Romania

### Lead Technical writer: January 2020 - Present

- Worked with cutting edge Blockchain technology including Smart Contracts, Cryptocurrency Tokens and BlockChain Database
- Worked on extracting business requirements from clients and translating them into technological requirements for our developers
- Redesigned the entire documentation architecture and implemented new standards
- Expanded and improved our client facing API documentation
- Worked on Application Architecture and Server Architecture design
- Developed and delivered end user guides, technical user guides and instructional material

- Developed technical marketing materials for our products and services
- Extracted and documented company work standards and best practices
- Developed promotional material for crypto currencies and tokens
- Translated client requirements into internal technical requirements
- Helped transition all company documentation from G-suite to Microsoft Office 365

### Sr. Technical writer: December 2020 - January 2021

- Designed and wrote on functional User Guides
- Designed and wrote technical User Guides
- Wrote mobile banking apps guides
- Wrote internal app guides

# Techie Leadership | Podcast

# Producer and host: March 2020 - present

- Interviewed some of the best and brightest leaders of technical people to find out what is the modern way of delivering cutting edge solutions on time and under budget
- Networked and reached out to leaders in their fields and convinced them to come on the show and offer great value related to leading technical people

# Feel It Services LLC | Iasi Romania

### Rails Department Head: June 2019 - March 2020

- Inherited two more legacy apps, one for Satellite DCP Distribution and one for DCP order fulfilment
- Trained and mentored the more junior team members
- Maintained direct client relationships
- Leveraged bash, terraform, ansible and docker for deployments

# Rails Software Engineer: January 2019 - June 2019

- Worked on a world leading Digital Cinema Package Distribution ecosystem
- Architected new features with a focus on backward compatibility and integration
- Expanded and improved our test suite
- Helped reduce hosting costs by 40% over time
- Updated legacy systems without breakage or business interruption
- Developed and maintained all the developer documentation
- Generated and maintained our Confluence spaces
- Reviewed my team members work and helped keep our codebase consistent

### Nimonik LLC | Montreal Canada

# Rails Software Engineer: March 2017 - December 2018

- Built and launched a B2B environment health and safety management application for out Fortune 500 customers
- Created international law scrapers and parsers
- Created a smooth process for extracting legislation headers and associating them with the correct law sections
- Used design patterns to separate business logic from the Rails framework
- Worked with modular design and reusable functionality
- Used TDD for new feature development. We maintained full test coverage and backward compatibility
- Leveraged JSON:API and generated standard compliant APIs which were very easy to consume

### Rails Developer: July 2016 - March 2017

- Worked on a legacy EHS application
- Maintained the frontend
- Fixed bugs both frontend and backend
- Launched new customer requested features
- Refactored code and increased the test coverage

# Furnica SRL | Iasi Romania

### Manager: November 2014- February 2016

- Managed our family business a vertically integrated foodstuffs business consisting of both industrial and retail sectors
- Hired and trained employees. Set workloads and priorities
- Helped launch new products and new company brands
- Increased sales and profits by reducing operational costs

## European House Of Quality AG | Copenhagen Denmark

### Remote Copywriter & Business Analyst: April 2014 – October 2014

- Redesigned the entire sales approach of the company
- Held interviews with our clients and extracted testimonials.
- Generated new sales materials and funnels by integrating the testimonials
- Helped increase sales by focusing on what our customers liked best about our product

# Volunteering

# ELSA Romania | Iasi Romania

Senior Member: July 2013 - present

- Kept in contact and consulted for the association
- Offered guidance and feedback
- Participated in seminars and conferences

### Member October 2009 - July 2013

- Helped organise international study visits to Bruxelles, Zagreb, Milan
- Organised the biggest fundraiser in our chapters' history. All the money was used to buy and deliver Christmas gifts for children at risk
- Reached out to european public authorities and obtained funds for study visits and educational programs
- Held high school seminars on law concepts, practices and studying law

### Education

### 2009 – 2013: Alexandru Ioan Cuza University, Iasi, Romania

BS in Law. Coursework included: - European Community Law, Private Corporate Law, Theory of International Relations, International Trade Law - Commercial Law, Intellectual Property, Private Corporate Law

### **Publishing**

### Technical Blog | Devslife

Devs Life Blog

A technical blog I started in 2016 and published on and off until 2019. It focuses mostly on programming concepts illustrated with ruby examples

### Leadership in tech Podcast | Techie Leadership

Techie Leadership Blog Spotify - techie Leadership

A leadership in tech podcast focusing on interviews with various tech leaders, company owners and high level consultants

### **Exporting Secrets**

amazon.com - Exporting Secrets

My family has been heavily involved in import-export during the early 90's and 2000's. This work contains a multitude of resources and legal frameworks for exporting your goods worldwide